Hey everyone and thanks for jumping back
into the cryptoverse.
Today we're going to talk about Ethereum
dubious speculation. If you guys like
the content, make sure you subscribe to
the channel, give the video a thumbs up,
and also check out the sale on into the
cryptoverse premium at into the
cryptoverse.com.
Also, if you are wanting to go to the
first ITC conference, uh, make sure you
get your ticket before September 1st as
prices will be going up on September
1st. Link is in the description below.
It'll be taking place in Miami. Main
conference day will be November 21st.
Let's go ahead and jump in. So, Ethereum
has had a really nice rally, right? So,
I want to talk about that. And
obviously, my views on Ethereum are
somewhat different from Bitcoin. We
explained that in the last video we did
on Ethereum. Uh, and you know, we've
talked about, you know, where Bitcoin
usually finds lows, where Ethereum does,
and and kind of how that's connected.
We've talked about the ETH Bitcoin ratio
and and how Ethereum is affected by the
stock market. So, what I want to do is
kind of go through what I'm seeing with
Ethereum right now and and just kind of
talk about what I would expect to see,
you know, throughout the rest of of the
year. So, Ethereum has had, you know, a
sizable drop all the way back down to
around 1,500.
If you look at the uh regression band,
right, which we, you know, follow, you
can see it it's tagged the lower part of
the regression band just like it's done
a number of times, right? It did it in
2019, uh did it in uh 2016 as well. And
then, of course, it also did it way over
here in 2015. Now, in 2015, 2016, and in
2019,
when it tagged it, it actually did it at
the very end of the year, right? Like in
December.
Last year, we went to sort of the fair
value area in April. And arguably,
Ethereum just rallied up to the quote
unquote fair value, right? which right
now according to this regression chart
is around 23 to 2400. So according to
this chart, Ethereum is more or less at
its quote unquote fair value. Right now,
if you look at the ETH Bitcoin pair, one
of the things that I always follow, and
I've been following this forever, and we
have videos on it back in 2019, is that
20-month moving average for it because,
you know, in 2019, we were tracking this
and then once we got this big move above
it in July of 2020, it was a big deal
because we finally broke through this
massive resistance that had been holding
Ethereum down against Bitcoin.
We're above it right now,
but we were also above it in August of
2025, right? And we closed above it and
then the next month we gave it right
back. So for the ETH Bitcoin ratio, it's
moving in the right direction, right? It
it is no doubt about it. It's moving in
the right direction. We would ideally
want to see another month or two where
it's able to hold at these levels
without just simply giving it right
back. Okay? because again it it gave it
all it gave it back in September 2025.
Who's who's to know if it's going to
happen in September of 2026 or not? But
this is something that it looks like
it's trying, right? I mean, this is the
best Ethereum's tried in a while to to
sort of break out against uh against
Bitcoin. Now, when I was looking at
this,
one of the things that's interesting is,
you know, how Ethereum has rallied off
of the lower part of the regression band
and now it's back up to right around
where it was back in April. Okay. Now,
the question is is what is the Ethereum
rally that we just had, is it, you know,
is it more like are we all the way down
here where it went to the low and now
we're back in business as long as
there's not a recession like the
pandemic or is it, you know, further up?
According to the chart, it would imply
that we're further in. Now, here's where
it gets tricky for Ethereum.
You could argue that Ethereum has been
exhausting the bears for a really,
really long time.
Okay, it has. I think that, you know, in
2027, I think there's a decent chance
Ethereum will will start to pick back up
and hopefully do well and going up into
2028, ideally putting in new all-time
highs. And and I I think there's a good
chance that could happen. The question
is is how do we finish this year? All
right. Now, I want to take you through a
couple of examples for the stock market.
How has how has the stock market
historically affected Ethereum? Now, if
you're new here, you might not have
heard me say this before. And again,
seasonality works about 70% of the time.
So, about 70% of the time, the things I
talk about as it relates to seasonality,
it ends up playing out. And everyone
when it does play out, no one really
thinks twice of it, right? They're like,
"Yeah, well, that was going to play
out." When it doesn't play out, a lot of
people freak out and they're like,
"Well, use that." No, this is about
seasonality. What what often happens,
not what has to happen. If you look at
the last several midterm years, you'll
see that in 2014, there was a correction
in stocks at the beginning of 2014
and at the end of 2014. Okay? If you
look at 2018, there was a correction in
stocks at the beginning of 2018 and the
end of 2018. In 2022, a correction at
the beginning and also at the end. In
2026, a correction at the beginning. And
now we're waiting to see do we get a
correction in stocks at the end of the
year. Now, whether there's certainly a
chance that the low is in for Ethereum,
and I would argue the chances that the
low is in for Ethereum are actually
higher than for Bitcoin. If you look at
last cycle, Ethereum actually bottomed
in the summer, right? So, who's to say
it can't just simply bottom in the
summer again, right? Right. I mean, I
I've said that earlier this year that
[clears throat]
the argument for a Bitcoin low does not
is not necessarily an argument for a low
to occur at the same time for everything
as we got a glimpse of that in 2022. So,
I want to go through how stock market
corrections can affect things like
Ethereum. All right.
In 2022, at the end of 2022,
the stock market dropped about 20%.
Okay? And in that 20% drop that started
in August going into October,
Ethereum during that period from August
really to the market cycle low dropped
about 50%. From the rally, from the from
the August high
to the low, it dropped about 50%. Again,
this is not, you know, you have to sort
of look, not even care about the
bullmark sport band. You have to
basically ignore the regression band and
just say, look, Ethereum back then had a
nice rally off the June low. We rallied
up about 100%. This time we've rallied
up about 70 and then we gave 50% of it
back. Not everything. It was a higher
low and then we went up. So when the
stock market back then when the stock
market corrected 20%
Ethereum corrected about 50
in 2014
Ethereum we don't have a chart for but
in 2014 Ethereum only dropped 10% or
sorry sorry sorry the stock market only
dropped 10%. % at the end of 2014. And
so a 10% drop would not have the same
effect. We have seen 10% drops. We've
seen other 20% drops. If you want to see
what Ethereum did during the S&P's last
20% drop, look no further than early
2025. Right? The S&P dropped about 20%.
And in early 2025, you go over to early
2025. Um, starting in in sort of late
2024, I guess, but then going into early
2025, Ethereum dropped about 60 to 70%.
A lot of that occurred before the stock
market drop. So, if you were just to
kind of take it from when the stock
market drop was actually happening, it
was about a 50% drop. So the argument
would be that a 20% drop in the S&P in
two examples
in 2022 and in 2025, a 20% drop led to
about a 50% drop in ETH.
A 10% drop though. We got a 10% drop
earlier this year, early 2026.
It's a little hard to measure because
Ethereum was obviously sort of in that
bare market, but just as measured from
that, it was also about a 50% drop.
Ethereum doesn't really like stock
market drops,
but there are examples where it's not as
bad. Okay? Like July 2023, the stock
market dropped about 10% and Ethereum uh
back then
only dropped about 25. So,
if the seasonality for the stock market
were to play out and you have a
correction by stocks in the back half of
the midterm year starting in August or
September, could be late September, that
would be the main risk for Ethereum. A
lot of the other things kind of have
already sort of arguably played out for
Ethereum. And it would it would have to
be something in the stock market. I I
think that would cause uh you know,
Ethereum to kind of question some of
that stuff. So, how far will the stock
market drop?
I could find evidence for both,
honestly. Like, and and again, this is
assuming you have a drop in stocks. If
you don't have a drop in stocks, then
the Ethereum low is highly likely in
already if there's no drop in stocks.
So, if there's no drop in stocks in
starting in in the next month or two,
then the odds of the low being in for
Ethereum are, you know, probably like
70%. All right.
If you get a 10% drop in stocks,
a 25% drop in Ethereum, which we have
seen on 10% drops, would would actually
print a higher low. it would be printing
the same type of thing that it did in
2022, right? Where you get a drop in
stocks and then we print a higher low.
If the stock market gets a 20% drop and
Ethereum drops by 50%,
that's where, you know, you could end up
putting in a a slightly lower low, but I
wouldn't expect it to be that much that
drastically below it would be my guess.
Now I can find examples for why it would
be 10% or why it would be 20 or even why
it wouldn't happen. The main rec the
main sort of reconciliation on a 10 sort
one of the
arguments for just simply a 10% drop
is if you look at US interest rates and
you sort of go back to the '9s which
there's some parallels between uh this
rate cycle and the '9s because in the
'90s they they lifted rates up kind of
like they did over here and then they
dropped rates and then after they
dropped rates they then raised rates by
25 basis points in March of 1997 And in
March of 1997, when the stock when the
Fed raised rates 25 basis points, uh the
stock market had a correction, but it
wasn't very bad. You know, it wasn't a a
major correction. It was just about, you
can see starting in February. So, a
month before the the rate hike occurred,
starting a month, it was about a 10%
drop. So if it's a 10 if all it is is a
10% drop and there's no idiosyncratic
crazy stuff going on in the cryptoverse
then the odds low for Ethereum are
considerably higher.
If you want to look at, you know, could
it be a larger drop? Like could it be,
you know,
more substantial, take a look at 2018,
right? So, in 2018, the stock market had
a about a 10% drop early in the year.
And if you look at it in 2026, it was
also about a 10% drop early in the year.
But then later in the year, in late
2018, it was a 20% drop. So if it ends
up being a 20% drop
by stocks, what's interesting about a
20% drop
is if you look at sort of this trend
line that the stock market has been sort
of moving up
throughout the uh throughout the years.
So let me fix it. So, if you look at
that trend line,
a 20% drop basically gets you to the
trend line. Now, that doesn't mean we
can't go up first. I mean, first of all,
the stock market could rally first.
Maybe it goes all the way up to like
8,000 and then drops 20% or something. I
don't know. But that would be kind of
like if and when that happens, that's
when Ethereum, you know, could could
simply get tested. And and the most
likely time for it to occur for the
stock market, if history is any
indication, would be the back half
of the back half of the midterm year,
right? So late Q3 kind of going into Q4.
You can see in 2018, the low didn't
occur until uh late December.
by the stock market. So, I think that
would kind of be that that risk. And I
was trying to think about this of like
what, you know, what could it be? And it
could be long in rates going up despite
their best attempts to try to get it to
stay down. Maybe that leads to fear that
the Fed's doing the wrong thing. Uh when
the market, you know, the market's
basically saying you need to raise rates
for inflation. The unemployment rate has
been going down. Uh perhaps there's some
type of like scary print that occurs
later in the year which leads to a stock
market correction. I'm not really sure.
I I I couldn't tell you exactly why in
2014 there is a stock market correction
over there. I know later in 2015 2016
there was recession scares which is what
led to those larger drops by the S&P. Um
2018 you can see the S&P had a 20% drop.
2022 it was a 20% drop. So, I think
that's kind of like the risk for
Ethereum is just simply there being a
correction in the stock market. But I
would argue that if there is a
correction in the stock market, it would
it would simply just do what it caused
Ethereum to do last time, right? Like we
were rallied up into August, came back
down on a stock market correction, but
then just continued, you know, back in
business. So, that's the argument,
right? We've had a nice rally. If the
stock market does get that correction,
you know, starting in the next month or
so, it could bring ETH back down. And
it's the it's the depth of the stock
market correction that would then likely
dictate the depth of of how far back
down Ethereum would go before it would,
you know, really start to be back in
business and and hopefully begin a a
fresh bull market. You can see Ethereum
has been testing this level several
times throughout the years, like the uh
the $1,500 level.
But I will say this, I mean, you know,
if the stock market gets that correction
and Ethereum comes back down, test some
of these levels, it'd be really hard not
to be bullish on it, you know, really
going into 2027. And there's already
precedent for Ethereum bottoming in the
summer, right? Like bottoming in June,
July. I mean, that's what it did last
cycle. So,
um,
you know, we'll see. We'll see kind of
how that how that plays out and and
whether Ethereum can can really
hold like it did last cycle, right,
during I mean, it held last cycle
through that stock market correction.
And even though that stock market
correction was 20%, it it printed a a um
a higher low.
Uh, even though it was it was a 50% drop
uh by ETH. I mean, a 50% drop by ETH
from here would actually get you to a
new low, but there's there's a chance
that Ethereum might have a little bit
further to go. I think in the short
term, though, the main area that
Ethereum sort of pushing up against is
that 200E moving average. That's where
Ethereum struggled with back in May and
that's where it is right now. Okay. So,
if Ethereum, if the stock market were to
get a correction and Ethereum were to
sort of stall out here, head back down,
and then kind of hold there through the
end of the year, it'd be really hard not
to then be like, well, that's just kind
of setting up for a nice breakout into
into 2027. So, that's more or less what
I'm thinking for Ethereum. the scarier
charts for Ethereum for me uh and why I
don't talk about it nearly as much as I
used to is that it just keeps bleeding
against like other things. So, if you
look at the Ethereum gold valuation,
this is the this is like the issue,
right? I mean, like we can get excited
about these rallies by ETH, but when you
look at it against something like gold,
you probably can understand like where
I'm coming from, right? Like it's hard
and and and people gave me a hard time
about this with altcoins last cycle
because I'm like, "Well, they're just
bleeding to Bitcoin." But every time
they would rally against Bitcoin,
everyone would get mad. But I'm like,
"Guys, they're just bleeding to to
Bitcoin." The issue I'm having with
Ethereum that I'd like to see change at
some point is that it's just been
bleeding to gold since 2021. And the
lows that were just put in by the
Ethereum gold valuation were actually
lower than where they were in 2022.
So it just makes it not as compelling as
it once was when it was generally going
up against gold, right? Like it's just
been bleeding to gold for essentially
the last 5 years. And and we haven't
really seen anything definitively
changed just yet. And if you look at it
against silver, which by the way, I
mean, silver had a massive correction
this year, but if you look at it against
silver, it's still below where it was in
June of 2022. And that's just kind of a
crazy thought to say that we are still
below the ETH silver valuation from 2022
despite the rally that Ethereum just
had. I mean, it really goes to show you
just how weak the entire asset class has
been. Now, if you go look at at Ethereum
ROI and stuff, like if you were to look
at say like the year-to- date ROI of
Ethereum,
so let's go take a look at that.
and you look at 2026 compared to 2022,
you can see that Ethereum had a sizable
rally, you know, around this time and
then it kind of stalled out a little and
then it got back in business the
following year. And then if you look at
2018, you can see it's diverged some
because around this time we had actually
went we were dropping rather than uh
going up, which is what we're doing now.
And so if you add the average of those
two midterm years, you can see the
Ethereum is not really tracking it the
best it was previously, but this move up
does not correspond to the move down we
had around this time during previous uh
midterm years. And if you measure it
from the low or maybe from the peak,
if you look at the ROI after the peak
for Ethereum,
you can see it's gone on pretty long
already, right? Like and even if if the
low was in the summer, it was only
marginally before the the low uh
previously.
So, you know, it's a little bit more
difficult with altcoins, admittedly.
Like if you look at some of these random
altcoins like the bare markets just are
very different, right? Like for XRP for
instance, cycle 2 it took it 800 days to
bottom. Uh cycle 3 it took it, you know,
430 days. Cycle one, it took it 350
days. Like it's just so different each
cycle. So it's a little bit harder with
altcoins to like look at the stuff and
and know, you know, how how valid is it?
Bitcoin seems to be a little bit more
predictable in that case. Whereas the
altcoin market, it's it's a little hit
or miss, you know, and so that's why I
don't put a lot of of I don't put as
much faith into it. If you look at it as
measured from the low for Ethereum and
go low to the next low, you know, this
is the current cycle, right? I mean,
it's already lasted well longer than the
prior two, even if the low was in July.
But again, that's more of a reflection
of just how
underperforming Ethereum has been this
past cycle that it that it actually did
go on far longer than what we saw in uh
in the prior ones. And also is because
it bottomed earlier, right? It bottomed
earlier, but then the issue is that it
didn't really I mean it it honestly
didn't really accomplish a whole lot
this cycle. Ethereum is not that far
above again where it bottomed out a full
cycle ago.
Trying to think there's anything else
and we could look at monthly returns for
ETH and see what we have going on there.
So in August we're already up about 31%.
You can see in 2025 we had a pretty good
August and then we just kind of gave it
back for the rest of the year. This is
not 2025. If you look at it just midterm
years. This is definitely the first
green August we've had.
So hopefully it can stay like that. Um,
but again, it's it's a little premature.
If you look at if you look at things
like USDT dominance, this is one of
those things that we track somewhat
closely, you can see that USDT dominance
just swept the low. And so, I guess the
the concern for Ethereum at the 200E
moving average is that if you look at
USDT dominance, it set a low in May of
2026 and then now it has swept that low
in August. And then if you look at what
happened in 2022, there was a low by
stable coin dominance right here in May.
And then the low was swept in August
during the merge rally. And then stable
coin dominance went up basically one
more time into November. And then that
kind of marked the low for Bitcoin even
though Ethereum continued to print a
higher low. So that would be kind of the
risk here for for ETH is that it it
stalls out temporarily at the 200WE
moving average, maybe regroups and then
pushes through a little bit later, but
we'll see. I mean, a lot of times when
you have a rally by Bitcoin or Ethereum
and you break through the bull market
support band, what happens the very next
week is instrumental in helping us to
understand whether the low is in or not.
Okay. So, what I mean by that is if you
look at Bitcoin, this big rally that we
just had, you see how it's well above
the bull market support band. If we
follow through this week, that would
make the case for the low being in far
stronger, right? It would look a lot
more like the end of 2022 going into
2023. It would look similar to the low
printed after the 2018 low as well,
where you just get a big move up above
the bull market support band. But there
are times and you can maybe visualize
this with two week candles a little bit
better. There are times where you get a
strong move like in July 2018 where
Bitcoin rallied about 30%.
And then in the next twoe candle it just
gave it all back. Okay. And and this
time Bitcoin's up about you know 23%.
It's above the bull market support band.
It was also above it in July 2018 as
well. And then we came right back down.
So, I'm a believer in this case of let
the candles tell us. If there's
something to this rally, we shouldn't
ignore it, right? And this is why DCANG
is the best thing. Shouldn't ignore it.
Look to see what the next weekly, the
next two week candle does. Historically,
if you see followth through, the odds of
the low being in go up considerably.
This two-week candle for Bitcoin isn't
going to close for another seven days.
So you can see in 2019 there was a big
twoe candle but then we closed back down
and we gave it right back.
I'm a big believer in that. Like let the
chart tell us in this case if this is
meaningful and if it is you would expect
to immediately see follow through and
not have it stall out. You would expect
to see USDT dominance break down, right?
Like if it if it wants to prove that
it's different than than 2022, USDT
dominance would need to break down right
here. And if it doesn't and it just
simply bounces like 2022, then what
what's likely happening in that case is
the stock market correction is playing
out, right? The stock market correction
plays out and then crypto gets one final
drop because of the correction in the
stock market and then once the
correction in the stock market is over,
then stable coin dominance then starts
to head back down. That's the argument,
right? So watch stable coin dominance
and then watch just to see what Bitcoin
does this week. And then for Ethereum, I
mean from a you know from a regression
point of view, it it's you know it looks
fine. Like it looks fairly attractive.
It also looked fairly attractive over
here in in 2019 and then we had this uh
pandemic scare. I'm not calling for a
pandemic. Um, but usually when you get
like a 10 to 20% drop in stocks, people
at least start speculating about
recessions, even if there's no longer
even if there's not really a recession
in sight, that's where people really
start to to speculate about it. And and
you know, that happened also in in 2015
as well, where Ethereum had a nice rally
and then it came right back into the
regression ban on recession fears, even
though the recession fears didn't even
fully materialize.
So, uh, those are my views on Ethereum.
You know, I I certainly
wouldn't be surprised if the low is in.
I I think it's just going to simply I
think that will the idea will be simply
tested as we get later into Q3 and
especially into Q4. If the stock market
correction actually materializes and in
the case that stock market correction
does not materialize, then absolutely I
would think the low is in for Ethereum.
If the stock market is only a 10% drop,
there is a really good chance that the
low is in for Ethereum. If the stock
market gives a 20% drop,
that's when it could get a little bit
iffier for Ethereum. Like if if it if
the stock market like reconnects with
that trend line down there and drops
20%. That's where it gets a little
iffier as to, you know, as to whether
the low is in. But again, like you know,
going into 2027, I I wouldn't think it
would make a lot of sense to be bearish
on a lot of these things. Just how do we
how do we finish out the year? Uh so
we'll see. Thank you guys for tuning in.
Subscribe again. If you're going to the
ITC conference, make sure you get your
ticket before September 1st as ticket
prices are going to go up. Then thank
you guys for tuning in. I will see you
next time. Bye.